Zarnab Mubarak

Lahore District, Punjab, Pakistan



zarnabrana@gmail.com



03311300048



linkedin.com/in/zarnab-mubarak-b95862176

Summary

Experienced Java Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Java, Management, Programming, Software Development, and Web Development. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Computer Science from University of Management and Technology - UMT.

Experience

systems Senior Software Engineer

Systems Limited

Oct 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Working as senior software engineer on Telecom domain. Currently working on Project of Telenor known as Digi Malaysia. This project is build using micro services architecture, services communicate with each other through Queues and Rest APIs. Actively participating in daily scrums and ongoing training sessions held on monthly basis.

Software Engineer

digitify

Oct 2021 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Worked as Software Engineer (java) with Digitify (https://digitify.com/) . Basically digitifty works in Fintech domain. They provide an application named as YAP Money App. They were technology partner of company in UAE named YAP (https://www.yap.com/pk/). Their Money App is currently live for UAE, along with that they were also making money app for Pakistan and Ghana. I was working in Ghana team.

The Money App was written in Spring boot using microservices architecture. The money app was using the process FSS (https://www.fsstech.com/) for transaction processing and ADB Bank (https://www.adb.org/). I was the owner of Processor service and cards service.

Software Engineer

CloudCard Inc.

Jan 2021 - Oct 2021 (10 months)

Worked as Software Engineer (java) with cloud cards. Worked in two main services one was settlement service and the other one was auth service. Basically settlement service was written using spring batch and scheduler. At the day of end we receive a file containing bulk of records and we have to process it using spring batch and many other functionalities inside it.

Secondly I was handling the auth service which was written by some other developer using spring boot oAuth

Associate Software Engineer

CloudCard Inc.

Sep 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 5 months)

Worked as a Associate Software Engineer (java) with cloud cards. Basically cloud cards works in Fintech domain. They provide Issuer Processor for Banks. They were also providing B2B for their client CBKC (https://www.centralbankkc.com) and were also providing ACH for their client APTO payments (https://www.aptopayments.com/).

Initially I was working on B2B.Basically their B2B product was written for different business like different banks wants to use different processor, so this product was made for any business depending upon the requirement, on that time there were three processor (i2c, cc and Galileo). I worked on different microservices including customers and cards. The Technoloy used in this project was spring boot along with open Api.

Secondly I worked in their main product which was issuer processor. Initially processor was built in J2EE but later on we moved it to spring boot. Project structure was modular and was loosely coupled. Later on gradually it was moved on spring boot. I worked on Rest APIs.



Java Devolper

TrangosLabs

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Worked as Full stack developer with Sweden's Tacton (https://www.tacton.com/) for their client WILO (https://wilo.com). They provide CPQ solutions for any kind of product. Their CPQ solution is artificial intelligence based and main framework is build on Spring Boot and Hibernate. Their main clients are Siemens [website: www.simens.com]. And wilo [website: www.willo.com].

The project directly associated with my leadership and team span in the field of development involving front end with(HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap), backend with(Java), databases(MYSQL,H2 Database), task Management with(JIRA) and Development under Git.

Following Agile Practices in their development Lifecycle. We works on Scrums, having two weeks sprints, daily meeting on Teams with customer and Proeject Manager. A monthly Retrospective on which we discuss what went well, what went wrong and how can improve.

Education



University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore

Masters in Computer Science, Computer Science Jul 2020 - May 2022

Completed Masters in computer Science with CGPA 3.40.



University of Management and Technology - UMT

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

2014 - 2018

Completed Software Engineering from University of Management and Technology with CGPA 3.87

Skills

Open API · Microservices · J2EE Application Development · AngularJS · jQuery · Hibernate · SQL • Liquibase • Spring Boot • Spring Batch

Honors & Awards

Employee Excellence - Systems Limited

Sep 2023

Got Kudos card from my competency for Good work.